Graham Beer

311 Fair Oak Road, Bishopstoke, Eastleigh, SO50 8JU

Mobile: 07740 822 214 / Email: Graham.Beer@outlook.com LinkedIn: uk.linkedin.com/pub/graham-beer/51/789/7a1

Blog: https://graham-beer.github.io/

Professional Profile

An experienced IT professional with over 18 years IT industry knowledge gained in Retail, Automotive Services and Education. A passionate and highly focused individual with an excellent wealth of knowledge in End User Services, Scripting, Systems Management and Automation, with excellent skills in PowerShell combined with SCCM (2012 & CB), Office 365 and Azure.

A keen technology enthusiast who dedicates time to continually learning about current and emerging areas of technology specifically DevOps, Azure, PowerShell DSC, Pester and C#.

Co-founded the UK South Coast PowerShell User Group in April 2017 and organised sponsorship.

Technical Skills

Development: PowerShell, Team Foundation Server (TFS), Git (and GitHub)

Software: Office 365. Azure

Build Automation: SCCM 2012 & current branch, MDT, Intune, Vagrant

Tools: Visual Studio 2015, Chocolatey,

Operating systems: Windows XP/7/8.1/10, Server 2003/2008/R2/2012/R2, Active Directory

Experience of writing SQL Reports

Good basic understanding of Networking concepts.

Career Highlights

- User interface development in PowerShell using WPF for Specsavers to simplify management of Office 365
- Upgraded SCCM 2012 R2 SP1 to SCCM current branch at The AA and Bournemouth University.
- Full accountability for AA's PC software and hardware estate relating specifically the Mobile Patrols IT Infrastructure.
- Delivery of a desktop transformation project impacting over 10,000 machines using SCCM, including Windows 8.1 builds, zero-touch deployment, managing, planning and engineering management services.

Career Summary

04/2017 - Present POWERSHELL DEVELOPER (Contract) Specsavers

- Multinational migration to Office 365 using PowerShell including configurations, mailbox data, policies, users, security and distribution groups.
- User interface development in PowerShell using WPF.
- Tool development for Service desk levels 1 and 2. Including:
 - Simplifying management of User account and mailbox creation.
 - · Configuration of multi factor authentication.
 - Creation and configuration of licenses based on Company roles.
 - · Group assignment based on role.
 - · Company role change.
 - Membership and preservation of mailboxes and OneDrive accounts for leavers.
- Programming of automated PowerShell scripts for user management and creation in both Azure AD and on-premise AD for integration with ADFS.

08/2016 - 31/03/2017 SENIOR TECHNICAL CONSULTANT (Contract) Bournemouth University

- Created customized reports in SCCM utilizing SQL/SQL Reporting services to help assist on desktop inventory.
- Created Desired Configuration Management (DCM) baselines.
- Design authority on best practices for SCCM 2012 including personal recommendations Automation.
- · Zero-touch builds using PowerShell scripting.
- Scripted automation of BIOS changes for HP Desktops to meet Bournemouth University standards across all desktops.
- Creation of Windows 10 build image using MDT for deployment in SCCM.
- Upgrade of SCCM 2012 to SCCM current branch.

10/2014 - 08/2016 SENIOR TECHNICAL CONSULTANT: DESKTOP The AA

- Lead Technical Administrator SCCM Current Branch environment.
- Created and editing security groups, application deployments (collections, advertisements, task sequences, and PowerShell scripts), and delivering patch management, general troubleshooting, log analysis, and upgrade and recommendations on current infrastructure.
- Providing technical expertise for a Windows 8.1 migration, package and application configuration/ deployment strategies, operating system deployment, and site hierarchy configuration settings.
- Installing and configuring Windows Server 2012 for SCCM.
- Contributing to operational changes such as upgrade from Office 2013 to Office 365.
- Developed organizational units in Active Directory (AD) and managed user security.
- Administering Intune for device management and delivery of applications and integration with SCCM.

01/2014 - 10/2014 CLIENT CONSULTANT DESKTOP MODERNISATION PROJECT B&Q / Kingfisher

- Managed and maintained Desktop builds using LANDesk Management Suite to facilitate £10million Desktop modernisation programme. Managed version control documentation across all PC builds.
- Maintained Windows 7, 8 and 8.1 images using ImageX and DISM tools.
- Created software packages encompassing scripting with batch files and PowerShell. Tested, scheduled and distributed packages using LANDesk Management Suite.
- Created Endpoint Protection Policy management using LANDesk Security Management Suite.

02/2007 - 01/2014 SENIOR CLIENT INFRASTRUCTURE ANALYST B&Q / Kingfisher

- Provided remote IT support including On-Call out-of-hours service for UK B&Q distributed estate.
- Managed ad-hoc software installation, machine rebuilds, and user gueries and requests.
- Installed software and applications, installed and configured peripherals, components and drivers, and configured and troubleshot desktops, laptops and servers.
- Worked with Active Directory maintaining user, group, and computer accounts, Group Policy.
- Troubleshooting of Network issues, including LAN/WAN, VLAN's TCP/IP/DNS, WINS, DHCP and VPN

06/2001 - 02/2007 RETAIL APPLICATION SENIOR SUPPORT B&Q

2nd Line IT support for UK B&Q stores including Windows and UNIX issues escalated from Service Desk.

Education and Qualifications

Professional Training and Certifications:

- Implementing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions (M20533)
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (M10979)
- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS): Administering and Deploying System Center 2012 Configuration Manager
- Administering System Center 2012 Configuration Manager (M10747)
- Windows 7, Enterprise Desktop Support Technician Course
- Bytes Fundamentals of Windows Server 2008 Course
- LANDesk Training Course: Overview of fundamentals, patching, deployment and AV management
- ITIL Course: Overview of widely-adopted approach to IT Service Management
- Advanced Information Technology and Intermediate Technology, GNVQ Level 3 Eastleigh College (1999)